Alice ran away?!
Yeah.
I think she might have
been overwhelmed by all
the interviews and things
we had scheduled for her.
I always checked with her to see if
she was tired and needed a break,
but she'd just smile and shake
her head and say she was fine.
I'll head to the Roppongi
office right now.
Once we find out where she's at,
we can all go get her together.
Now what?
Alice!
You need to sign for it.
It's from Wrath.
I wonder what they sent me.
Would you stop making so much
noise and kindly unpack me?
Now, please.
Jeez, Alice.
Everyone's worried sick about you.
I know.
I am sorry about that.
It was very childish.
I was desperate to speak with you alone.
And not in your virtual form,
but your real physical self.
Just you and I, face to face.
Kirito.
I am so angry with you.
Why did you not tell me
you were staying behind?
and of the possibility
you would never return.
If you had told me before I
reached the altar, I would have...
I would have...
I would have stayed and not fled here!
I am still a knight.
Fighting evil is my duty.
So why...
Why did you face him alone?
A dreadful foe like that,
what were you thinking?
Why did you not want me there,
by your side, assisting you?
Who do you think I, Alice
Synthesis 30, am, if not capable?
Who am I in your eyes?
That's easy.
You're my hope.
And you're not just my hope.
The Underworlds, too.
All the people who lived and died there.
A hope that can't be replaced.
I didn't want to lose you.
I wanted to protect you so that
hope could last for the future.
Really?
This future, what do you
think it will look like?
If I can endure the loneliness
and chaos of this world,
trapped inside this body made of steel,
what kind of future could
there possibly be for me?
Sorry.
I wish I had an answer for that, but...
I know that you being here
will change the world,
and you'll change it for the better.
And when all's said and
done, Cardinal's hopes,
and Administrators,
and Bercouli's, and Eldrie's, and Eugeo's
too, will finally become a reality.
That's what I believe.
We must contact Rank at once.
It simply will not do to
make her worry further.
Mm-hmm. Good idea.
Hey.
Yeah, she's here. She's
fine. Uh-huh. Sure.
Okay, bye.
She says hi.
Don't worry, she's not upset.
She feels bad, you know, for
all you're going through.
She also said you can spend
the night here, if you want it.
She said I could? Really? Yep.
If that is the case, I would like
you to show me around your home.
You will, won't you?
I have never seen the inside of a
real-world dwelling space before.
Sure, no problem.
But like, it's not really that special.
There's not a whole lot more to see.
Actually, you'll like this part of it.
Amazing.
Is this a training hall?
Uh-huh.
But in this world, we call it a dojo.
A dojo.
Interesting.
Such a peculiar training sword.
Quite different from
those in the Underworld.
Oh?
What's up?
Take it.
This is a training hall.
Let us make use of it.
Wait, what?
I don't know about this.
Are you used to that body?
No need to hold back.
Do you remember?
The day you and I first crossed swords in
the garden on the 80th
floor of the cathedral.
Yeah, you clobbered the
hell out of me back there.
I'm not gonna let that happen again.
I win again.
Thanks to my ultimate
skill, the steel headbutt.
I never heard of that one before.
I just invented it.
I will be alright now, Kirito.
I know I can survive in this world.
Wherever I go, I will be myself
as long as I can wield a sword.
I have realized that my fight is
not over yet, and neither is yours.
So I will look forward, and only
forward, and keep moving ahead.
Then Kazuto tripped and fell. Really?
It is hard to believe he was so clumsy.
Oh, he was.
I could tell you stories.
Kazuto, we have a lot to talk about.
First things first, I believe you owe
your mother and I a proper apology.
Father, Mother, I didn't
mean to make you guys worry.
I'm really sorry.
We're used to it by now.
Besides, this time, what you were doing
was something very important, right?
If you say you're going
to do something, do it.
It's the same with writing a
book or sticking to a deadline.
Oh, Mom, that's your experience.
Your mother left something out.
For days, she had no idea where you were,
and she was getting sick from worrying.
I understand the importance
of what you accomplished.
However, that does not
mean you get a pass.
Kazuto, where should your focus be now?
On high school. That's it. Exactly.
And that's where you should be
putting all of your efforts,
not just during class,
but all the time. I know.
I have to study hard and get into college.
It's already the summer
of your junior year.
Your mother said you wanted to
go to America and study there.
Is that still your plan?
Well, I was thinking about that and...
I'm sorry.
I sort of changed my mind.
Sort of how?
I still want to major in
electrical engineering,
but here, at Toto Institute, actually.
After that, I want to work at, or,
I mean, the Oceanic Exploration
and Research Institute.
Father, excuse me?
When I first presented myself
as a knight to my father,
I am sure he had his reservations.
Through my actions, I proved to
him the depth of my conviction.
And I am sure in the end, he understood
my choice to remain a knight.
Kirito, or rather Kazuto, also
follows the path he believes is just.
And I know this, because despite being
an ordinary student in this world,
in my world, he was the
greatest swordsman of all.
One who fought gallantly to
protect countless others.
He is a hero.
Alice.
Yes, I know.
In fact, his mother and I know
about everything he's done.
He's as much of a hero in
this world as he was in yours.
Aren't you, Black Swordsman?
Kazuto.
To choose a path, to study, to
attend a university and get a job.
Those are just part of a process
and the fruits of your labor,
but it's okay to change your mind.
Just try to live without regrets.
That's all we expect of you.
I will, promise.
Thanks, Dad.
Thanks, Mom.
Kirito, wake up.
Kirito.
Huh?
Alice! Shh!
Would you lower your voice?
Yeah, sorry, it's just that...
What are you doing here?
Wearing next to nothing.
I...
I demand you stop leering!
Alright.
It's late. What's up?
Approximately five minutes ago, while I
was connected to your so-called network,
I received an alarming communique via
your world's remote messaging formal art.
Email? Who's it from?
It had no name ascribed to it.
They wrote...
Actually, it would be
quicker if you read it.
What the hell?
Yui, are you up?
I am now, Daddy. Good morning.
Sorry to wake you.
I need a favor. Sure.
Check this out.
Interesting.
These are the names of floors
in the Central Cathedral.
Yes.
Training Hall 2 is Floor 52.
Media Storage is Floor 68.
The Senate is on 96.
Geographical Records is Floor 58.
Look at that.
An IP address. Yes.
It seems the white
tower to climb is the IP
address you deciphered
from the second line.
If that's so, you're supposed
to follow it to reach Yon World.
So basically, it says this
address is pointing to a server.
Yeah, that's it. I get it now.
Here it is.
It's the way back there.
This is the path leading
to the Underworld!
The way back? Really?
Then that means we can...
I can return to my world.
My home. My people.
Yeah.
Now that that's settled, I was thinking
when we go back to the Underworld,
Um, is it cool if Asuna comes along too?
I suppose so.
If we find ourselves in danger,
we'll need as many warriors
at our disposal as we can get.
Here it is.
Funny.
I get the feeling he might be behind this.
Me too.
He probably is.
Yui, did you find anything
else out about that address?
I could only get as far as
the server's relay point.
The firewall it has is super tough, so
I couldn't go any further. It's okay.
You tried.
Well, it's time we dove in.
We shouldn't be in any danger.
I think.
If you get in trouble,
I'll swoop in and save you!
Damn right you will.
Okay, see ya.
Remember, a couple
hundred years have passed.
The Human Empire and Dark Territory
could be way different now.
Watch your backs in there, okay?
Okay, but Administrator ruled
the Human Empire for 300 years.
That's a bit longer than we've been gone.
I doubt it's changed all that much.
When we log in, the first thing
we'll do is go wake Selka up.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, Kirito. Asuna.
All right, guys.
Are you ready to dive in? Ready!
What's this?
We were in outer space!
Kirito, look there.
No way!
Underworld!
Land of my birth!
Land where I was nurtured and raised!
Hear me now!
At last, I have returned to you.
Your daughter...
HAS RETURNED!
Laura! You okay? Come in!
Hasty, I'm here.
I'm okay for now, but my ship's not.
She's on her last leg.
That's it, then.
You have to eject.
The thrusters on your flight suit
should get you back to Garden.
No way!
That's not happening.
I can't just abandon her!
You're right. You can't.
We're gonna fight to the end, then.
You and me.
Roger that.
It's a...
a man!
He can't fight that thing
with a couple swords.
Release recollection.
Release Recollection!
Did they kill it?
I think they killed it.
That monster's not dead yet.
Watch out!
It's getting away!
We have to burn it up
before it regenerates!
That Swordsman...
That knight...
I've seen her before.
Yeah, so have I.
It's Lady Alice.
Release recollection.
She did it.
Oh my gosh!
Do you look it?
Do you see him?
The man wearing black! I know him!
Yeah, Laura.
I do too.
What color of your soul
is the color of your soul?
I don't know.
Thank you.